Register of the John Davis Lodge papers, 1886-1987
Hoover Institution Archives
John Davis Lodge papers
1886-1987
86005
Hoover Institution Archives
288 manuscript boxes, 26 oversize boxes, 3 cubic foot boxes, 1 card file box, 3 album boxes, 121 envelopes, 2 sound cassettes, 1 sound tape reel, 1 sound disc (155.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, dispatches, reports, memoranda, clippings, other printed matter, photographs, sound recordings, and motion picture film relating to the Republican Party, national and Connecticut politics, and American foreign relations, especially with Spain, Argentina and Switzerland.
Lodge, John Davis, 1903-1985.
Access
Boxes 310-311 closed. The collection is stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu.
Use copies of some sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To access other sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1903 October 20 Born, Washington, D.C.
1921 Graduated, Middlesex School
1925 B.A., Harvard University
1929 J.D., Harvard University Married Francesca Braggiotti
1929-1931 Associate, Cravath, deGersdorff, Swaine and Wood, New York
1932-1942 Actor, motion pictures and theatre
1942-1945 Captain, U.S. Navy (liaison officer to Free French Naval forces, North Africa)
1946-1950 Lawyer, American Economic Foundation, New York Member of Congress from Connecticut
1950-1954 Governor, Connecticut
1953-1955 Special Presidential Ambassador, Panama, Costa Rica, Puerto Rico
1955-1961 Ambassador to Spain
1965 Delegate, Connecticut Constitutional Convention
1969-1974 Ambassador to Argentina
1983 Member of U.S. Delegation to the United Nations
1983-1985 Ambassador to Switzerland
1985 October 29 Died, New York City
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, speeches and writings, dispatches, reports, memoranda, clippings, other printed matter, photographs, sound recordings, and motion picture film relating to the Republican Party, national and Connecticut politics, and American foreign relations, especially with Spain, Argentina and Switzerland.
Reagan, Ronald.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); United States. Congress. House.; United States. Dept. of State.; Argentina; Argentina--Foreign relations--United States.; Connecticut--Politics and government.; Diplomats--United States.; Phonorecords.; Phonotapes.; Spain; Spain--Foreign relations--United States.; Switzerland--Foreign relations--United States.; Switzerland.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; United States--Foreign relations--Argentina.; United States--Foreign relations--Spain.; United States--Foreign relations--Switzerland.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; United States--Politics and government.
- Early Life (1903-1932) File, 1886-1932, 1976 (Boxes 1-6)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material (including Lodge's education and family background), correspondence, and speeches and writings.
  - Biographical file, 1886-1932, 1976, undated
    - Education
      - Ecole Gory, 1914 (Box-folder 1: 1)
      - Middlesex School, 1915-1917
        - Class notes and papers (Box-folder 1: 2-2a)
        - Programs, school song, etc. (Box-folder 1: 3)
      - Boy Scout Camp, notes, 1916 (Box-folder 1: 4)
      - Camp Pasquanay, program and notes, 1924 (Box-folder 1: 5)
      - Harvard University
        - Class Day program, regulations, library card, 1924 (Box-folder 1: 6)
        - Class notes and papers, 1922-1927 (Box-folder 1: 7-10)
        - Clippings about John D. Lodge, 1924 (Box-folder 1: 11)
        - Grade reports, 1922-1925 (Box-folder 1: 12)
        - Law School, class notes, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 1: 13)
        - Cercle Francais (Box-folder 2: 1)
        - Hasty Pudding Club (Box-folder 2: 2)
        - Miscellany, 1922-1928 (Box-folder 2: 3)
          Includes memorandum about Count Hermann Keyserling.
        - Tuition receipts, 1923-1925 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - Engagement and marriage, clippings, 1928 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - Law practice, 1929-1932
      - General (Box-folder 2: 6)
      - Admission to the bar (Box-folder 2: 7)
      - Court cases
        - Alpha Realty vs. Gaffney (Box-folder 2: 8)
        - Beer-Hoffman vs. Jones (Box-folder 2: 9)
        - Briggs & Braggiotti vs. Sheridan (Box-folder 2: 10)
        - Munroe vs. Montgomery (Box-folder 2: 11)
        - Ogden vs. Jenkins (Box-folder 2: 12)
        - Pinchot vs. Pinchot (Box-folder 2: 13)
      - Legal agreements
        - Affidavit for transfer of property, etc. (Box-folder 2: 14)
        - Articles of partnership (Box-folder 2: 15)
        - Certificates of incorporation (Box-folder 2: 16)
        - Powers of attorney (Box-folder 2: 17)
        - Representation agreement (Box-folder 3: 1)
        - Wills (Box-folder 3: 2)
      - Research memoranda, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 3: 3-4)
    - Lodge family
      - George Cabot Lodge
        - Appointment to U.S. Navy (Box-folder 3: 5)
        - Biography, Crowley, John, Biography of George Cabot, Twayne Publishers, Boston, 1976 (Box-folder 3: 6-16)
        - Book contract (Box-folder 3: 17)
        - Clippings (Box-folder 3: 18)
        - Correspondence
          - General (Box-folder 3: 19)
            Includes correspondence regarding the poetry of George Cabot Lodge.
          - Barton, George, 1895 (Box-folder 4: 1)
          - Bell, Helen C., 1898-1909 (Box-folder 4: 2)
          - Berry, Walter, 1903-1908 (Box-folder 4: 3)
          - Beveridge, Albert J., 1905 (Box-folder 4: 4)
          - Flandrau, Charles, 1894-1909 (Box-folder 4: 5)
          - Mitchell, Langdon, 1895-1908, undated (Box-folder 4: 6-9)
            Includes clippings.
          - New England Society, 1906 (Box-folder 4: 10)
          - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1896 (Box-folder 4: 11)
          - Spring-Rice, Cecil, 1902 (Box-folder 4: 12)
          - Stickney, Eliza B., 1898-1900 (Box-folder 4: 13)
        - Writings, reviews of "Cain" (Box-folder 4: 14)
      - Henry Cabot Lodge, Sr. (Box-folder 4: 15)
      - Matilda Elizabeth, 1900-1910 (Box-folder 4: 16)
        Includes poem written to commemorate the birth of a son to Mr. and Mrs. George Lodge.
      - Miscellany, 1886-1926 (Box-folder 4: 17, 5: 1)
        Includes clippings, poetry, notebook, and passport.
  - Correspondence, 1889-1932
    - General
      - undated (Box-folder 5: 2-3)
      - 1912-1914 (Box-folder 5: 4)
      - 1915 (Box-folder 5: 5)
      - 1916 (Box-folder 5: 6)
      - 1918 (Box-folder 5: 7)
      - 1919 (Box-folder 5: 8)
      - 1922 (Box-folder 5: 9)
      - 1923 (Box-folder 5: 10)
      - 1924 (Box-folder 5: 11)
      - 1926 (Box-folder 5: 12)
      - 1927 (Box-folder 5: 13)
      - 1929 (Box-folder 5: 14)
      - 1930 (Box-folder 5: 15)
      - 1931 (Box-folder 5: 16)
      - 1932 (Box-folder 5: 17)
    - Adkins, Leonard, 1931 (Box-folder 5: 18)
    - Boal, Pierre de, 1932 (Box-folder 5: 19)
    - Braggiotti, Dorilio, 1931 (Box-folder 5: 20)
    - Braggiotti, Isidore, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 5: 21)
    - Braggiotti, Mario, 1931 (Box-folder 5: 22)
    - Brisbane, Arthur, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 5: 23)
    - Cravath, Paul D., 1931-1932 (Box-folder 5: 24)
    - Crocker, Mr. and Mrs. Edward, 1926-1932 (Box-folder 5: 25)
    - Davis, G.H., 1919 (Box-folder 5: 26)
    - Dewey, Thomas E., 1931 (Box-folder 5: 27)
    - Dodge, Wendell Phillips, 1931 (Box-folder 5: 28)
    - Eames, Hamilton, 1923-1926 (Box-folder 5: 29)
    - Eames, Mrs. Hayden, circa 1926 (Box-folder 5: 30)
    - Etting, Emlen, 1928 (Box-folder 5: 31)
    - Frelinghuysen, George G., 1889-1924 (Box-folder 5: 32)
    - Frelinghuysen, Lucy, 1915-1918 (Box-folder 5: 33)
    - Gardner, A. P., 1915 (Box-folder 5: 34)
    - Hurst, Brian, 1932 (Box-folder 5: 35)
    - Jacques, Henriette, 1927 (Box-folder 5: 36)
    - James, Mrs. Ellerton, 1926 (Box-folder 5: 37)
    - Knight, Richard, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 5: 38)
    - Lodge, Francesca, 1928-1932 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Lodge, G. D., undated (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Lodge, Helena, 1919-1929 (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Sr., 1912 (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1919-1931 (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - Lodge, J. E., 1925 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - Lodge, Matilda Elizabeth, 1916-1931, undated (Box-folder 6: 7-11)
    - McCloy, John J., 1931 (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - Perrin, Ernest, 1927 (Box-folder 6: 13)
    - Sampsell, Marshall, 1927 (Box-folder 6: 14)
    - Sanchez, Eduardo, 1924 (Box-folder 6: 15)
    - Winslow, Alan F., 1931-1932 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Speeches and writings, 1923-1927
    - Notes and drafts, 1925 (Box-folder 6: 17)
    - Letter to The Hartford Courant, printed copy, undated (Box-folder 6: 18)
    - Letter to Harvard Crimson, printed copy, 1923 February 1 (Box-folder 6: 19)
    - "Tuberculosis," handwritten draft, circa 1926 (Box-folder 6: 20)
    - Review of "L'Avare," Harvard Crimson, printed copy, 1926 December 2 (Box-folder 6: 21)
    - Letter to Harvard Crimson, printed copy, 1927 January 20 (Box-folder 6: 22)
- Motion Picture and Theatre Career (1932-1942) File, 1931-1942 (Boxes 7-11)
  Biographical material (including clippings of performance reviews), correspondence, speeches and writings, and general subject material.
  - Biographical file, 1932-1942, undated
    - Passport and Certificate of Registration (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Clippings
      Includes reviews, advertisements, programs, and correspondence.
      - General, 1932-1942 (Box-folder 7: 2-6)
      - Amphitryon, undated (Box-folder 7: 7)
      - Bank Holiday, 1938 (Box-folder 7: 8)
      - Bulldog Drummond at Bay, 1937 (Box-folder 7: 9)
      - Caprice, 1940 (Box-folder 7: 10)
      - Just Like a Woman, 1940 (Box-folder 7: 11)
      - Koenigsmark, 1935 (Box-folder 7: 12)
      - Lightning Conductor, 1939 (Box-folder 7: 13)
      - Little Colonel, 1935 (Box-folder 7: 14)
      - Little Women, 1933 (Box-folder 7: 15)
      - Mayerling to Sarajevo, 1940 (Box-folder 7: 16)
      - Menace, 1934 (Box-folder 7: 17)
      - Night of Love, 1941 (Box-folder 7: 18)
      - One Night in Paris, 1940 (Box-folder 7: 19)
      - Ourselves Alone, 1936 (Box-folder 7: 20)
      - Pasha's Wives, circa 1942 (Box-folder 7: 21)
      - Pirate of the Seven Seas, 1940 (Box-folder 7: 22)
      - Premiere, 1939 (Box-folder 7: 23)
      - Queer Cargo, 1938 (Box-folder 7: 24)
      - Sarajevo, 1940 (Box-folder 7: 25)
      - Scarlet Empress, 1934 (Box-folder 7: 26)
      - Sensation, 1937 (Box-folder 7: 27)
      - Stasera alle 11, undated (Box-folder 7: 28)
      - Sweet Racket, 1938 (Box-folder 7: 29)
      - Tenth Man, 1936 (Box-folder 7: 30)
      - Three on a Weekend, undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
      - Tonight or Never, undated (Box-folder 8: 2)
      - Watch on the Rhine, 1942 (Box-folder 8: 3-4)
    - Contracts (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - Resumes (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Correspondence, 1932-1942
    - General
      - 1932-1933 (Box-folder 8: 7)
      - 1934 (Box-folder 8: 8)
      - 1935-1938 (Box-folder 8: 9)
      - 1938 (Box-folder 8: 10)
      - 1939 (Box-folder 8: 11)
      - 1940 (Box-folder 8: 12)
      - 1941 (Box-folder 9: 1)
      - 1942 (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - Actor's Equity Association, 1939 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - Associated British Picture Corporation, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - Braggiotti, Gloria, 1932-1934 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - British International Pictures, 1937 (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - Burns, Ward, 1932-1940 (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - Dandi, Roberto, 1937 (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - Drouin, Dominique, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 9: 9)
    - Eames, Hamilton, 1939 (Box-folder 9: 10)
    - Edington, Harry E., 1932-1939 (Box-folder 9: 11)
    - Endicott, William C., 1936 (Box-folder 9: 12)
    - Etting, Emlen, 1939 (Box-folder 9: 13)
    - Gale, Marland, 1939 (Box-folder 9: 14)
    - Hellman, Lillian, 1941 (Box-folder 9: 15)
    - Ives, Colin, 1939 (Box-folder 9: 16)
    - Jacques, Henriette, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 9: 17)
    - Jeffreys, Winifred G., 1937 (Box-folder 9: 18)
    - Kurrock, Dudley, 1936 (Box-folder 9: 19)
    - Lebedeff, Ivan, 1939 (Box-folder 9: 20)
    - Lee, Norman, 1937 (Box-folder 9: 21)
    - Lodge, Francesca, undated (Box-folder 9: 22)
    - Lodge, Helena, 1936 (Box-folder 9: 23)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1932-1940 (Box-folder 9: 24)
    - Lodge, J.E., 1937 (Box-folder 9: 25)
    - Lodge, Matilda Elizabeth, 1932-1940 (Box-folder 9: 26-27)
    - Marchetti, Roger, 1935 (Box-folder 9: 28)
    - O'Bryen, Linnit and Dunfee, 1934-1938 (Box-folder 9: 29)
    - Ottone, Giorgio, undated (Box-folder 9: 30)
    - Perrin, Ernest, 1933-1936 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - Rabb, Maxwell, 1941 (Box-folder 10: 2)
    - Ramey, Pierre de, 1937 (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - Schooling, Picot, 1937 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - Schuster, Harold, undated (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - Toenges, Evelyn V., 1936-1938 (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Trives, A., 1937 (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - Tuscherer, Eugene, 1939 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - Vincent, Frank, 1939 (Box-folder 10: 9)
    - White, William L., undated (Box-folder 10: 10)
    - Williams, Constance, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 10: 11)
    - Williams, Paul W., 1941 (Box-folder 10: 12)
    - Winslow, Alan, 1933 (Box-folder 10: 13)
  - Speeches and writings, 1933-1942
    - 1933 (Box-folder 10: 14)
    - 1934 (Box-folder 10: 15)
    - 1935 (Box-folder 10: 16)
    - 1936 (Box-folder 10: 17)
    - 1937 (Box-folder 10: 18)
    - 1939 (Box-folder 10: 19)
    - 1940 (Box-folder 10: 20)
    - 1942 (Box-folder 10: 21)
  - Subject file, 1931, 1935-1941, undated
    - Abyssinia, 1935 September 1 (Box-folder 10: 22)
      Cyril Rocke, open letter to the Archbishop of Canterbury.
    - Barter Theatre Award, program, 1941 (Box-folder 10: 23)
    - Cook, Thomas & Son, undated (Box-folder 10: 24)
      Polan Banks, "The Man From Cook's," typescript.
    - Cravath, Paul, 1931 (Box-folder 10: 25)
      Letters on his travels in India, Southeast Asia and China.
    - Drama League of New York (Box-folder 10: 26)
    - Equity agents (Box-folder 10: 27)
    - Ethiopia, 1935 (Box-folder 10: 28)
      Mobilization proclamation by Haile Selassie.
    - George VI, King of Great Britain (Box-folder 10: 29)
    - Lebedeff, Ivan (Box-folder 10: 30)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1937 April 18 and 1940 February 12 (Box-folder 10: 31)
      Radio address, and speech to Associated Republican Clubs of Kings County, typescript.
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 10: 32)
    - Naval duties, 1939 (Box-folder 10: 33)
    - Ophuls, Max, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 10: 34)
      Correspondence relating to Ophuls' emigration.
    - Perrin, Ernest (Box-folder 10: 35)
    - Reynolds, Robert (Box-folder 10: 36)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin, 1939 September (Box-folder 10: 37)
      Printed copy of Roosevelt's address to Congress.
    - Scripts, undated (Box-folder 10: 38, 11: 1)
    - Summer stock, 1940
      - Manhattan Repertory Theatre Company (Box-folder 11: 2)
      - South Shore Players (Box-folder 11: 3)
    - U.S. Marine Corps (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - Webster, Daniel, undated (Box-folder 11: 5)
      Excerpts from the Bunker Hill Monument Address.
    - White, Lawrence P. (Box-folder 11: 6)
- U.S. Navy Service (1942-1945) File, 1940-1945 (Boxes 11-14)
  Biographical material (including Lodge's family), correspondence, office materials, speeches and writings, and general subject material.
  - Biographical file, 1942-1945, undated
    - Biographical sketches (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - Clippings about John Davis Lodge (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - Clippings, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 11: 9)
    - Education (Box-folder 11: 10)
    - Family
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 11: 11)
      - Pourtales, de (Box-folder 11: 12)
    - Naval award ceremonies (Box-folder 11: 13)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1945
    - General
      - 1942 (Box-folder 11: 14)
      - 1943 (Box-folder 11: 15)
      - 1944 (Box-folder 11: 16)
      - 1945 (Box-folder 11: 17)
    - Aldrich, Richard S., 1942-1944 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Banks, A. Polan, 1942 (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - Benton, William, 1945 (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - Braggiotti, Mrs. Mario, undated (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - Casey, John T., 1942 (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - Christians, Mady, 1945 (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - Dewart, Thomas G., 1942-1944 (Box-folder 12: 7)
    - Duffy, Charles, 1944 (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - Dupre, Dallas, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - Eames, Hamilton, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 12: 10)
    - Etting, Emlen, undated (Box-folder 12: 11)
    - Fenard, Vice Admiral, 1945 (Box-folder 12: 12)
    - Forrestal, James, 1944 (Box-folder 12: 13)
    - Frelinghuysen, Matilda, 1944 (Box-folder 12: 14)
    - Friendly, Edwin S., 1945 (Box-folder 12: 15)
    - Gimbel, Mrs. Bernard, 1942 (Box-folder 12: 16)
    - Hewitt, Vice-Admiral Henry K., 1944 (Box-folder 12: 17)
    - Ives, Colin C., 1945 (Box-folder 12: 18)
    - Kiely, Thomas B., 1943-1945 (Box-folder 12: 19)
    - Korndorfer, Raymond L., 1942-1945 (Box-folder 12: 20)
    - LaForgue, Rene, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 12: 21)
    - Lambert, Rear Admiral, 1944 (Box-folder 12: 22)
    - Lebedeff, Ivan, 1945 (Box-folder 12: 23)
    - Lodge, Francesca, undated (Box-folder 12: 24)
    - Lodge, George Cabot, 1945 (Box-folder 12: 25)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 12: 26)
    - Lodge, Mathilda Elizabeth, 1942 (Box-folder 12: 27)
    - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1942 (Box-folder 12: 28)
    - Mentz, G. Francis, 1945 (Box-folder 12: 29)
    - Noel, Sterling, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 12: 30)
    - Rabb, Maxwell, 1942 (Box-folder 12: 31)
    - Sinon, Frank, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 12: 32)
    - Steele, Bernard, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 12: 33)
  - Office file, 1940-1945, undated
    - Despatches (Box-folder 12: 34)
    - Directive, regulations for war correspondents (Box-folder 12: 35)
    - Directory (Box-folder 12: 36)
    - Memoranda, 1940-1945 (Box-folder 12: 37-40)
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 12: 41)
    - Personnel (Box-folder 12: 42)
    - Press releases (Box-folder 12: 43)
    - Reports
      - Naval aviation in the Pacific war (Box-folder 12: 44)
      - Operation "Avalanche" (Box-folder 12: 45)
      - Wartime history of the Public Relations Office (Box-folder 12: 46)
  - Speeches and writings, 1942-1945
    - General (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - Notes, research materials, and drafts, undated (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - Speeches, undated (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - 1942 (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - 1943 (Box-folder 13: 5-6)
      Includes notes.
    - 1944 (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - 1945 (Box-folder 13: 8-12, 14: 1)
      Includes notes, speeches for others written by John Davis Lodge, and typescript and holograph draft of unpublished book "There Is a Tide."
  - Subject file, 1943-1945, undated
    - Algiers, undated (Box-folder 14: 2)
      William Strand, "Algiers, Paris of This War," typescript.
    - American Economic Foundation (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Censorship, 1945 May (Box-folder 14: 4)
      "Code of Wartime Practices for the American Press and Radio," printed copy.
    - Communist Party, United States (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Connecticut, 1943 (Box-folder 14: 6)
      War Council, typescript of Chapter 10b of manuscript.
    - Crusaders, pamphlet, undated (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - Defense, 1945 October 29 (Box-folder 14: 8)
      Admiral William F. Halsey, Jr., speech, typescript.
    - Draft, undated (Box-folder 14: 9)
      Captain M.M. Witherspoon, "Universal Military Training," typescript.
    - French Navy, 1944 (Box-folder 14: 10)
      Marine Nationale.
    - Gaulle, Charles de (Box-folder 14: 11)
    - Industry and government, 1945 March 8 (Box-folder 14: 12)
      Assistant Secretary of the Navy H. Struve Hensel, speech, typescript.
    - League of Nations, 1944 January 30 (Box-folder 14: 13)
      Henry Cabot Lodge Jr., "Lessons From a Historic Debate", New York Times Magazine, printed copy.
    - Lodge, John Ellerton (Box-folder 14: 14)
      Correspondence on the death of John E. Lodge. Includes poetry.
    - Luce, Clare Boothe (Box-folder 14: 15)
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 14: 16-17)
    - Montgomery, Douglass (Box-folder 14: 18)
    - Morgan, Major John, 1943 (Box-folder 14: 19)
      "Why Are We Fighting?," typescript.
    - Newspaper strike, New York City, 1945 (Box-folder 14: 20)
      Statement and excerpts by Edwin S. Friendly.
    - Poetry (Box-folder 14: 21)
      Miscellaneous poems about World War II.
    - PRO-Com Three (Box-folder 14: 22)
    - Red Cross (Box-folder 14: 23)
    - Red Cross in the Pacific, World War II, 1945 March 21 (Box-folder 14: 24)
      Secretary of the Navy James Forrestal, speech, typescript.
    - Republican Party (Box-folder 14: 25)
    - United States
      - Armed Forces, 1945 March 8 (Box-folder 14: 26)
        Rear Admiral DeWitt Clinton Ramsey, "Service in the Armed Forces," speech, typescript.
      - Navy
        - Vice Admiral Henry Kent Hewitt, "Amphibious Assault, a History of the United States Navy's Participation in the Invasion of Sicily," vol. l, typescript, 1943 July (Box-folder 14: 27)
        - Miscellany (Box-folder 14: 28)
        - Mutual Aid Association (Box-folder 14: 29)
        - Navy Relief Society (Box-folder 14: 30)
        - USS Tarawa (Box-folder 14: 31)
    - Voice of America, 1945 October 30 (Box-folder 14: 32)
      William Benton, speech, typescript.
    - War production, 1943 April 7 (Box-folder 14: 33)
      Rear Admiral C.H. Woodward, speech, typescript.
    - Willkie, Wendell (Box-folder 14: 34)
- U.S. Congress (1946-1950) File, 1945-1950 (Boxes 15-30)
  Biographical material (including Lodge's congressional election campaigns), correspondence, office materials, speeches and writings, and general subject material.
  - Biographical file, 1946-1950, undated
    - Appointment calendars, 1948 and 1950 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Awards (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - Biographical sketches (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - Campaign, 1946
      - General (Box-folder 15: 4)
      - Clippings (Box-folder 15: 5-8)
      - Committees (Box-folder 15: 9-10)
        General and Lodge for Congress Committee.
      - Convention (Box-folder 15: 11)
      - Election statistics (Box-folder 15: 12)
      - Finances (Box-folder 15: 13)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 15: 14)
      - Nominating speech and acceptance speech (Box-folder 15: 15)
      - Opponent (Box-folder 15: 16)
      - Platform (Box-folder 16: 1)
      - Press releases (Box-folder 16: 2)
      - Publicity (Box-folder 16: 3)
      - Schedules (Box-folder 16: 4)
      - Statistical analysis (Box-folder 16: 5)
      - Voter lists (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - Campaign, 1948
      - Advertisements, handouts, stationery, campaign literature (Box-folder 16: 7)
      - Committees (Box-folder 16: 8-9)
      - Connecticut State Central Committee (Box-folder 16: 10)
      - Convention committee (Box-folder 16: 11)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 16: 12)
      - Endorsements (Box-folder 16: 13)
      - Financial records (Box-folder 16: 14)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 16: 15)
      - Nomination (Box-folder 16: 16)
      - Opponent (Box-folder 16: 17)
      - Press releases (Box-folder 17: 1)
      - Radio announcements (Box-folder 17: 2)
      - Republican National Committee (Box-folder 17: 3)